nostarch.com 2019-07-04

# Privacy Policy | No Starch Press

We take your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy explains the way that we collect, use, and disclose your personal information and our commitment to you with respect to our use and disclosure of non-personal browsing and site usage data that we collect. That is, information that would allow a party to identify you including, for example, your name, address or location, telephone number, or email address. By accessing or using any of the Services, you agree to the practices described in this document.

### About Us

No Starch Press is a California Corporation. Our primary business is that of publishing books. Our physical address and other contact information is:

No Starch Press  
245 8th Street  
San Francisco, CA 94103 USA  
+1 415.863.9900  
fax: +1 415.863.9950  

If you have any questions about our privacy policy please direct them to our Business Manager at the address listed above.

### Our Commitment to You  

We are committed to handling the information and data we collect about you with care, whether it is personal information or non-personal browsing and site usage data. 

  1. We will collect only the minimum amount of information necessary to provide you with services, and only for as long as necessary.
  2. We will not use information that you provide or that we gather as a result of your use of our site for marketing or advertising purposes unless you agree to that use, and we will not provide that information voluntarily, without your permission, to anyone else unless required by law.
  3. If we are required to provide a third party with your personal information (whether by subpoena or otherwise), we will attempt to notify you promptly of that event, unless prohibited by law or if we are advised not to do so on the advice of legal counsel.

### Personal Information We Collect

We may collect personal information through our website, including without limitation when you sign up to receive updates from us, subscribe to one of our email lists, purchase merchandise, or create an account or establish an ID on our website.

When you purchase something from our online store you will need to provide us with certain personal information including your name, e-mail address, telephone number, address(s), credit card type, number, expiration, and CVV2 value). We store your contact information in our database and tie it to your account but we do not store your payment information. Your payment information is captured directly by our payment gateway.

### What Is Personal Information?

Personal information is defined as information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual. An identifiable individual is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, by reference to an attribute such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier, or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person. 

### You Have a Choice, Always

We value your privacy and want to ensure that you have choices on how we use your personal information to communicate with you, send you marketing information, how we provide you with customized and relevant advertising, and whether you want to stay signed into your account. 

### How to Access and Control Your Data

We highly regard your right to access, control, correct, request deletion or request restriction of how we use your data as required by applicable law. Thus, we take necessary steps to ensure that the personal information we collect is accurate and up to date. At all times, we will provide you with a copy of your personal information, update information when requested, inquire about the personal information we maintain on you, and will act immediately upon a request for deletion or restriction or your personal data. 

### Cookies

Our site uses Drupal and Ubercart which uses cookies to keep track of your session with us when you log in, visit a particular page, or add an item to your shopping cart. Our site is also connected to Cloudflare and uses Google Analytics, both of which may set cookies in your browser. We do not use cookies for marketing purposes.

  * To learn how Google Analytics sets cookies in your browser and how Google uses that information, read this document: [https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs...](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage)
  * To learn how Cloudflare sets cookies in your browser visit this page: <https://www.cloudflare.com/cookie-policy/>

### Use of Your Personal Information

When you subscribe to updates from us, your email address is stored in a database hosted on our hosting company’s server that can only be accessed by No Starch Press staff and contractors. When you subscribe to one of our email lists and give us permission to do so your name and email address may also be sent to and stored in another service such as Mailchimp or similar in order to send you news and advise you of special promotions. We send these out infrequently and you can unsubscribe at any time. (If you don’t see an Unsubscribe link in an email please email us at [info@nostarch.com](mailto:info@nostarch.com) and we will remove you promptly from our marketing lists.)

We use your personal information to establish and maintain your account, to provide you with certain features, and to email you regarding changes to this policy or other applicable policies. If you sign up to receive updates from us when you create your account, we may use your personal information to send you news and promotional campaigns. 

When you register to obtain a user account on our website you may be asked to provide personal information to create your account and establish a password. We encourage you to use an alias or nickname if you are not comfortable providing your legal name. We may use the information you provide when you register your account to attribute any purchases you make to you but we will not provide that information voluntarily to a third party without your permission or unless we are required to do so.

### Disclosure of Personal Information

We will only disclose your personal information to third parties when you purchase something from our online store or when required to do so by law. When you place an order on our online store our shopping cart will pass your contact and order information to our payment processor and we will pass your contact details to our shipper if you order a physical product. 

We may disclose your personal information to third parties in a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (b) comply with the law, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order; or (c) to protect our rights, reputation, and property, or that of our users, affiliates, authors, or the public. If we are required to provide a third party with your personal information we will attempt to notify you promptly of that event, unless prohibited by law or if we are advised not to do so by legal counsel.

### Security of the Personal Information We Collect

Our entire site uses end-to-end SSL encryption and is protected by an EV SSL certificate. Do not enter information at our site unless your browser indicates that the page you are using is secure by displaying a lock icon or similar in the address bar. We have implemented reasonable measures to protect against unauthorized access to and unlawful interception or processing of personal information that we store and control, but no website can fully eliminate security risks. If there is a security breach of our site or a third party intercepts or accesses transmissions or private communications we will post a notice to our site.

Our site supports logins via OpenID but you should know that OpenID services may be vulnerable to DNS attacks, and use of OpenID may increase the risk of phishing. You’ll find a nice summary of the risks here: <https://sites.google.com/site/openidreview/issues>

### Non Personal Browsing Information We Collect

Our site is hosted by a third party. When you use our site we may collect information about your activities indirectly and automatically (through, for example, the use of your IP address) while visiting our site, including information about the browser you are using.We use this information for internal purposes only, such as to help understand how our site is used, to improve our services, and for systems administration purposes. We use Google Analytics and may use other third party analytics providers to help us collect and analyze non-personal browsing information for the same purpose. You may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Ad settings here: <https://www.google.com/settings/ads>

We do not sell or otherwise voluntarily provide the non-personal browsing information we collect about you or your website usage to third parties, except as required by law as discussed above.

### No Access

We are able to log into your account on our site to review or adjust your orders, your access to eBooks, and similar, but we will not use this technical login ability for any other purpose unless required to by law.

### No Retention

We do not retain your non-personal browsing information in server logs once we have used that information for the limited purposes noted above.

### Account Termination

Upon your request we will terminate your account at [https://nostarch.com](https://nostarch.com/) and remove all personal information. In order to terminate your account please email [info@nostarch.com](mailto:info@nostarch.com) and we will let you know what we will require in order to terminate your account.

### Notice

If we are required to provide a third party with your non-personal browsing information or to log in as you by law we will use reasonable means to notify you promptly of that event, unless we are prohibited by law from doing so or are otherwise advised not to by legal counsel. 

### Reorganization or Spin-Offs

We may transfer some or all of your personal and/or non-personal browsing information to a third party as a result of a reorganization, spin-off, or similar transaction. Upon such transfer, the acquirer’s privacy policy will apply. In such event, we will attempt to notify you and to ensure that at the time of the transfer the acquirer’s privacy policy is consistent with ours.

### Children

Our website is not directed at children under 13. Consistent with the federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personal information from anyone under the age of 13 without requiring parental consent. Our Terms of Use specifically prohibit anyone using our site from submitting any personally identifiable information about persons under 13 years of age. Any person who provides their personal information our website represents that they are 13 years of age or older.

### Third-Party Sites

Some pages on this site may include links to other websites. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party sites when you visit them as this Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites.

### Note to International Users

Our website and your eBook downloads are hosted in the United States though they may be cached and delivered by Cloudflare. By providing your personal data you consent to the use of your personal data for the uses discussed above.

### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. When we do, we will also revise the effective date below. We encourage you to periodically review this policy to stay informed about how we protect the personal information we collect. Your continued use of our website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.
